Register of the Russell Gerard Davis Papers, 1949-1988.
Hoover Institution Archives
- COUNTRY REPORTS
  - Salvador
    - Salvador. Ministerio de Educacion. Oficina de Planeamiento y Organizacion, "Analisis Sectorial de la Educacion en el Salvador" (Contd.)
      - Documentos Estadisticos de Trabajo
        - No. 6A. "Calculos de Eficiencia de la Educacion Basica Basados en Estimaciones de Costo y Resultados de la Prueba Nacional: Sector Publico," 1976 (Folder 5)
        - No. 6B. "Calculos de Eficiencia de la Educacion Basica Basados en Estimaciones de Costo y Resultados de la Prueba Nacional: Sector Privado," 1976 (Folder 6)
        - No. 7. "Estimaciones de las Necesidades y de las Disponibilidades de Espacio Fisico para la Educacion Basica," n.d. (Folder 7)
        - No. 8. "Calculos de Cobertura de Espacio Fisico para la Educacion Basica Basados en Estimaciones de Necesidades y Disponibilidades," n.d. (Folder 8)
        - No. 9. "Las Matriculas Iniciales y Finales y Estimaciones de los Costos de la Parvularia Sabatina," n.d. (Folder 9)
        - No. 11. "Estimaciones de Actitudes y Comportamientos de los Directores y Supervisores de las Escuelas de Educacion Basica y sus Relaciones con los Resultados de la Prueba Nacional," 1976 (Folder 10)
        - No. 12. "Tabulaciones de las 24 Pruebas Nacionales en Terminos de las Frecuencias de Repuestas Correctas y Incorrectas, el Tipo y Area de las Preguentas, y las Correlaciones de las Preguentas con el Resultado Total de la Prueba," 1976 (Folder 11)
        - No. 13. "Metas Hipoteticas de Matricula y Estimaciones de sus Recursos y Costos en Base a Niveles Preestablecidos de Mejoramiento en la Repeticion y la Utilizacion de Aulas y Maestros y Distintos Niveles de Mejormiento en la Desercion Permanente, 1976-2002," n.d. (Folder 12)
        - No. 13A. "Estimaciones de Recursos y Costos de las Metas Hipoteticas de Matricula sin Mejoramientos en la Repeticion y/o en la Utilizacion de las Aulas y los Maestros, 1976-2002," n.d. (Folder 13)
      - Documento General de Trabajo No. 4. "Programacion," 1974 (Folder 14)
      - Documento Metodologico de Trabajo No. 7. "Educacion No Formal," 1977 (Folder 15)
      - Warwick, Donald P., and Noel McGinn, "Educational Sector Analysis in El Salvador: Progress and Impact," 1977 (Box 17., Folder 1)
    - Yang, Shao-hua, "A Study of the El Salvadorian Labor Force and Its Implications for the Human Capital Theory," 1978 (Folder 2)
    - Charts (Folder 3)
    - Memoranda (Folder 4)
    - Statistics (Folder 5)
    - Student paper proposals (Folder 6)
  - Saudi Arabia
    - "Instructional Notes on School Mapping," n.d. (Folder 7)
    - McCabe, James
      - "Design for a School Mapping Study in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia," 1979 (Folder 8)
      - "Notes on School Mapping and Regional Planning of Education," 1976 (Folder 9)
    - "Manpower and Education Policy Planning in Saudi Arabia: An Executive Summary of Work with the Compound Model," n.d. (Folder 10)
    - Saudi Arabia. Ministry of Planning, "Development Plan, 1400-1405 A.H.: Planning Manual," 1978 (Folder 11)
    - Seifelnasr, Ahmed, "Demographic Analysis and Projections Mission, Saudi Arabia," 1978 (Folder 12)
    - "The Use of the Compound Model in Preparing the Third Development Plan," n.d. (Folder 13)
    - World Bank. Technical Assistance and Special Studies Division. Europe, Middle East and North Africa Projects Department (Folder 14)
      - "A Brief Overview, Explanation and Illustrative Uses of the Compound Model: An Integrated Computer Based Manpower Forecasting Model," 1979
      - "Enrollment Flow Models and Policy Planning with the Compound Model," 1978 (Folder 15)
      - "Saudi Arabia Manpower Planning Study (Stage II)," 1978 (Folder 16)
      - "Third Development Plan: Overview of the Human Resource Sector Plan," 1979 (Folder 17)
    - Miscellany (Folder 18)
  - Senegal. Beardsley, John, "The Youth Project of Ronkh, Senegal: A Cooperative Development Effort," 1978 (Folder 19)
  - Singapore. Diamond, J., "The Economic Impact of International Tourism on the Singapore Economy," 1979 (Folder 20)
  - Thailand. Snyder, Hugh, "The Michigan State University-AID Project with the National Economic Development Board, Government of Thailand, 1964-1968," 1979 (Box 18., Folder 1)
  - Upper Volta. Daniere, Andre, "Potential for USAID Assistance to the Government of Upper Volta in the Areas of Education and Training," 1977 See also Mauritania (Folder 2)
  - Venezuela. McGinn, Noel F., and Russell G. Davis, "Human Resource Development in Ciudad Guayana, Venezuela," 1967 (Folder 3)
  - Yemen. Cohen, John M., and David B. Lewis, "Rural Development in the Yemen Arab Republic: Strategy Issues in a Capital Surplus Labor Short Economy," 1979 (Folder 4)
- GENERAL REPORTS
  - Anderson, Lascelles (Box 18.)
    - "Allocation Models in Educational Planning," 1978 (Folder 5)
    - "The General Linear Model," 1978 (Folder 6)
  - Beardsley, John, "Beneficiary Participation in Rural Education Programs," 1978 (Folder 7)
  - Beirn, Russell, David C. Kinsey, and Noel F. McGinn, Antecedents and Consequences of Early School Leaving: An Analytical Survey of Research Activities, 1972 (Folder 8)
  - Bowles, Samuel, "A Class Analysis of Resource Allocation in Education," 1978 (Folder 9)
  - "Compass," n.d. (Folder 10)
  - Daniere, Andre, "Identification of Country Objectives, and Reconciliation with Objectives and Strategies of U.S. Assistance," 1978 (Folder 11-13)
  - Davis, Russell G. (Box 19.)
    - "Delphi Exploration of Future Goals, Activities, Patterns of Organization, Approaches and Support in Development Assistance and Education," n.d. (Folder 1)
    - "Education and Work: Prospects for Change," n.d. (Folder 2)
    - "Enrollment Projections in Education Planning," 1978 (Folder 3)
    - "Forecastig for Computer Aided Career Decisions: Survey of Methodology," n.d. (Folder 4)
    - "Instruction, Research, and Service in the Center for Studies in Education and Development," 1979 (Folder 5)
    - "Instructional Notes on School Mapping and Area Planning," 1978 (Folder 6)
    - "Planning Education for Employment," 1978 (Folder 7)
    - "Policy and Program Issues Raised by the Application of Compound Models," 1978 (Folder 8)
    - "Population Projection and Demographic Analysis: A Background Manual for Instruction and Reference," 1978 (Folder 9)
    - "Present Status and Future Developments of Models for Educational Planning," 1972 (Folder 10)
    - "The Social Demand Approach to Educational Planning," n.d. (Folder 11)
    - "Usefulness of Macro Level Manpower Requirements Planning," 1978 (Box 19., Folder 12)
    - "With a View to the Future: Tracing Broad Trends and Planning," 1979 (Folder 13)
  - Davis, Russell G., and Barclay Hudson, "Issues in Human Resource Development Planning: Research and Development Possibilities," 1979 (Folder 14)
  - Davis, Russell G., and Ernesto Schiefelbein, "Area Planning and School Mapping: Background to the Methodology," n.d. (Folder 15)
  - DeHasse, Jean, "Morphological Mapping: A Methodology for Increasing the Fit Between Planning and Implementation," 1979 (Folder 16)
  - Diamond, J., "Econometric Modelling of Development Processes," 1979 (Folder 17)
  - Durstine, Richard M., and Russell G. Davis, "Educational Planning in Developing Countries: A Possible Role for Operations Research," 1969 (Box 20., Folder 1)
  - "Economic Growth Studies," n.d. (Folder 2)
  - "Educational Systems Models and Enrollment Flow Models," n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "Goal and National Purpose In Planning," n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Gordon, Lester E., et al., "Interim Report: An Assessment of Development Assistance Strategies," 1979 (Folder 5)
  - Gordon, Polita C., "A Resource for Developing a Plan to Increase the Enrollment of Female Students in Non-Traditional Shops in Public Vocational-Technical High Schools," 1979 (Folder 6)
  - Harman, David, "Planning the Nonformal Educational Strategy: Content and Curriculum Design," 1978 (Folder 7)
  - Hudson, Barclay, "Compact Policy Assessment and the Compass Method: Practical Application of Dialectical Theory to Educational Planning and Forecasting," 1979 (Folder 8-9)
  - "Issues in Human Resource Development Planning: Speculation, Research Questions and Program Responses," n.d. (Folder 10)
  - Jenkins, Glenn P., "Inflation and Cost-Benefit Analysis," 1978 (Folder 11)
  - Jenkins, Glenn P., and Claude Montmarquette, "Estimating the Private and Social Opportunity Cost of Displaced Workers," 1978 (Folder 12)
  - Judy, Richard W., "Simulation and Rational Resouce Allocation in Universities," n.d. (Folder 13)
  - Keyfitz, N., "Evolution of Educational Systems," 1980 (Folder 14)
  - Kline, David, "Introduction to Nonformal Education and its Planning," 1979 (Folder 15)
  - Kocher, James and Richard A. Cash, "Achieving Health and Nutritional Objectives with a Basic Needs Framework," 1979 (Folder 16)
  - Lewis, Gary
    - "Analysis of Categorical Cross-Classified Tables of Counts," 1978 (Folder 17)
    - "Beyond the General Linear Model," 1978 (Folder 18)
    - "Categorizatin of Analysis Techniques," 1978 (Folder 19)
    - "Data Analysis: Objective Science or Abstracted Empiricism?" 1978 (Folder 20)
    - "Data Analysis for Educational Planning: A Case Analysis," 1978 (Box 21., Folder 1)
    - "Explanatory Analysis of Cross-Classified Continuous Data," 1978 (Folder 2)
    - "Log-Linear Models," 1978 (Folder 3)
    - "Preparatory Steps for Computer Data Analysis," 1978 (Folder 4)
    - "Scheduling," 1978 (Folder 5)
    - "Visual Data Displays," 1978 (Folder 6)
  - McGinn, Noel (Folder 7)
    - "Information Requirements for Educational Planning: A Review of Ten Conceptions," 1979
    - "Types of Research Useful for Educational Planning," 1978 (Folder 8)
  - McGinn, Noel, and Donald Snodgrass, "A Typology of Implications of Planning Education for Economic Development," 1979 (Folder 9)
  - "Manpower Requirements Models and Methods for Planning: Manual and Instructional Case," n.d. (Folder 10)
  - Middleton, John, "Transnational Instructional Development: Models for Planning and Management," 1977 (Folder 11)
  - Picker, Hans, "The Concept of Relevance: A Programmatic Definition," 1978 (Folder 12)
  - "Planning Method and Educational Substance," n.d. (Folder 13)
  - Schiefelbein, Ernesto, "Estimation of Enrollment Flow Rates: Five Methods and Their Application," 1978 (Box 22., Folder 1)
  - Simmons, John, "Help or Hindrance? Education in Developing Countries," 1975 (Folder 2)
  - Simmons, John, and Henry Noerenberg, "The Income Benefits from Schooling: A Multiple-Equation Analysis," 1977 (Folder 3)
  - Sjaastad, Larry A., and Daniel L. Wisecarver, "The Little-Mirrlees Shadow Wage Rate: Reply," 1979 (Folder 4)
  - Snodgrass, Donald
    - "The Distribution of Schooling and the Distribution of Income," 1978 (Folder 5)
    - "Types of Economic Development Strategy and Their Relationship to Educational Planning and Technical Assistance," n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Snyder, Hugh, "Lessons for AID Derived from Case Studies (Peru, Thailand, Turkey) of AID-University Projects in Educational Planning," 1979 (Folder 7)
  - Stern, Joseph J., "Outline and Interim Report," 1973 (Folder 8)
  - "Strategy of Internal Efficiency Analysis: Partial Mapping of Efficient Combinations of Direct Outcomes and Cost," n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Truesdell, Elizabeth, and Mary Hyde
    - "A Computer Coded Model for Population Projection (An Interactive System)," 1978 (Folder 10)
    - "Computer Coded Models for Forecasting," 1978 (Folder 11-12)
    - "Data Management Systems," 1978 (Box 23., Folder 1)
  - Turksen, Ismail B., and Albert G. Holzman, "Micro Level Resource Allocation Models for Universities," 1970 (Folder 2)
  - U.S. Agency for International Development
    - "A.I.D. Use of Development Indicators: A Progress Report," 1973 (Folder 3)
    - Evaluation Handbook, 1972 (Folder 4)
  - Untitled writing on cybernetics, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Warwick, Donald (Folder 6)
    - "Analyzing the Transactional Content for Planning," 1978
    - "Integrating Planning and Implementaton: A Transactional Approach," 1978 (Folder 7)
  - Windham, Donald, "Planning: An Alternative Conception," 1978 (Folder 8)
- MISCELLANY
  - Appendices (Box 23., Folder 9)
  - Bibliographies (Folder 10)
  - Charts (Folder 11)
  - Computer manuals (Folder 12)
  - Fragments of writings (Folder 13)
  - Indexes (Folder 14)
  - Memoranda (Folder 15)
  - Outlines (Folder 16)
- CARD FILE
  - Card File. (Box 24.)
- Incremental materials (Box 25-33)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.